<resources>
    <string name="app_name">scan</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

    <!--beaus Nails -->
    <string name="Descbeaus">Beau\'s lines are horizontal indentations on the nails, indicating disruptions in nail growth. Their severity can suggest the seriousness of an underlying health issue. Faint lines on one or two nails may result from minor illnesses or stress. Multiple or deeper lines could indicate more serious health problems, such as nutritional deficiencies or prolonged stress. Very deep lines on all nails might signal serious systemic conditions, like severe infections or chronic diseases.</string>

    <!--black Nails -->

    <string name="Descblack">Black nails can appear in colors like black, brown, or dark purple and may show up anywhere on the nail, often near the cuticle. The discoloration can be linear, spotty, or diffuse. It may be accompanied by pain, swelling, or structural changes, especially if caused by trauma or infection. Mild cases, typically from minor trauma, usually resolve on their own. Moderate cases, due to more significant trauma, fungal infections, or medication side effects, may require treatment. Severe cases, with persistent or extensive discoloration, could indicate serious conditions like subungual melanoma or other systemic diseases, warranting medical attention.</string>


    <!--blue Nails -->
    <string name="Descblue">Blue nails can indicate poor circulation and are sometimes caused by cold temperatures, leading to temporary blue discoloration. More serious causes include respiratory and heart conditions like asthma, chronic bronchitis, congenital heart defects, or heart disease, which can result in moderate cyanosis due to low oxygen levels in the blood. Severe hypoxia from conditions such as advanced COPD, severe pneumonia, or pulmonary embolism, as well as severe circulatory issues like peripheral artery disease or deep vein thrombosis, can lead to significant cyanosis. Persistent cyanosis may also result from serious cardiopulmonary disorders, including heart failure or pulmonary hypertension.</string>

    <!--Clubbing Nails -->

    <string name="Descclubbing">Clubbing nails are marked by the enlargement of fingertip tips and a noticeable curvature of the nails, resulting in rounded and bulbous nails. The angle between the nail and the nail bed increases, and the nails may become shiny and spongy. This condition develops gradually and can affect both hands. Lung diseases like chronic bronchitis, lung abscesses, and cystic fibrosis can cause noticeable clubbing due to chronic oxygen deprivation. Heart diseases, such as congenital heart defects or endocarditis, can also lead to moderate clubbing. Severe clubbing is often linked to serious lung conditions like lung cancer, interstitial lung disease, or pulmonary fibrosis, as well as advanced heart diseases and conditions like inflammatory bowel disease or cirrhosis. Severe clubbing warrants medical attention to diagnose the underlying cause.</string>

    <string name="deschelthy"> Healthy nails are smooth and uniform, with no pits, grooves, or ridges. They have a consistent light pinkish color from the underlying blood vessels, and the nail plates are neither too thick nor too thin. The lunula, a half-moon shape at the nail base, is usually visible and well-defined, especially on the thumbs.</string>

    <string name="Deschyperkeratosis"> Hyperkeratosis is a condition where the skin under the nails thickens due to an overproduction of keratin, a protein in skin, hair, and nails. Affected nails often become thick, rough, and discolored, ranging from white to yellowish-brown. In mild cases, there may only be slight thickening without significant discomfort. Severe hyperkeratosis can be linked to underlying conditions like psoriasis, fungal infections, or other systemic diseases. </string>

    <string name="DescParonychia">Paronychia is another nail abnormality, characterized by an infection around the nail fold. It may be bacterial or fungal, causing redness, swelling, and pain. In mild cases, there is localized redness and swelling without pus formation. In moderate cases, there is increased swelling, pain, and possible pus formation. In severe cases, there is significant pain, extensive swelling, and systemic symptoms such as fever.</string>

    <string name="Descsplinter">Splinter hemorrhages are small, red or brown lines that appear under the nail plate due to bleeding from capillaries. In mild cases, there are isolated splinter hemorrhages with no associated symptoms. In moderate cases, multiple splinter hemorrhages are present, possibly indicating underlying conditions. In severe cases, there is extensive hemorrhaging associated with systemic diseases like endocarditis. </string>


    <string name="DescTerry">Terry\'s nails appear mostly white with a narrow pink band at the tip, often associated with systemic illnesses like liver disease. In mild cases, there is slight whitening with minimal pink band. In moderate cases, there is more pronounced whitening and a wider pink band. In severe cases, there is complete whitening with no visible lunula, indicating serious systemic issues.</string>

    <string name="DescTrachyonychia">Trachyonychia, or "twenty-nail dystrophy," involves rough, thin nails that may be associated with psoriasis. In mild cases, there is minor roughness with no significant nail thinning. In moderate cases, there is noticeable roughness and thinning of the nails. In severe cases, there is severe nail dystrophy affecting all nails, leading to significant cosmetic concerns.</string>

    <string name="DescYellow">Yellow nail syndrome is characterized by yellow discoloration, often associated with respiratory conditions. In mild cases, there is slight yellowing with no other symptoms. In moderate cases, there is more pronounced yellowing, possibly with nail thickening. In severe cases, there is extensive yellowing, thickening, and potential nail loss.</string>

    <string name="Desckoilonychia">Koilonychia, or spoon nails, presents with nails that curve inward, often linked to iron deficiency anemia. In mild cases, there is minor curvature with no associated symptoms. In moderate cases, there is more pronounced curvature and potential discomfort. In severe cases, there is significant curvature leading to nail fragility and potential breakage.</string>

    <string name="DescLeukonychia">Leukonychia involves white streaks or spots on the nails, often due to trauma or systemic conditions. In mild cases, there are few small white spots with no other symptoms. In moderate cases, there are multiple spots affecting several nails. In severe cases, there is extensive white discoloration covering most of the nail.</string>

    <string name="DescMedian">Median nail dystrophy results in a longitudinal ridge or split in the nail, often due to trauma or chronic irritation. In mild cases, there is a minor ridge with no pain or discomfort. In moderate cases, there is a more pronounced ridge affecting nail integrity. In severe cases, there are deep splits or cracks leading to potential nail loss.</string>

    <string name="DescMuehrcke">Muehrcke lines are transverse white lines that appear on the nail bed, often associated with hypoalbuminemia. In mild cases, there are few lines with no associated symptoms. In moderate cases, there are multiple lines indicating nutritional deficiencies. In severe cases, there are extensive lines suggesting significant systemic illness.</string>

    <string name="DescPitting">Nail pitting involves small depressions on the nail surface, commonly associated with psoriasis. In mild cases, there are few pits with minimal nail texture changes. In moderate cases, there are multiple pits affecting nail appearance. In severe cases, there is extensive pitting leading to crumbling or loss of the nail.</string>
    <string name="melanoma">Subungual melanoma is a rare and aggressive form of melanoma that occurs beneath the nail, often appearing as a dark streak or lesion. It is more common in toenails and can be mistaken for benign conditions like trauma or fungal infections. As it progresses, the nail may lift, change shape, or become brittle. Risk factors include previous trauma, skin cancer history, or genetic predisposition. Diagnosis involves biopsy, and treatment typically requires surgical removal, possibly followed by chemotherapy or immunotherapy. Early detection is critical for a better prognosis.</string>

    <string name="DescTumor">Nail tumors can present as growths under or around the nail, potentially indicating benign or malignant conditions. In mild cases, there are small, benign growths with no symptoms. In moderate cases, there are larger growths that may cause discomfort or changes in nail shape. In severe cases, there are malignant tumors with significant symptoms, requiring urgent medical attention.</string>
    <string name="Descony">Onychomadesis is a condition where the nail plate separates from the nail bed, leading to nail shedding or loss. It can be caused by trauma, infections, systemic illnesses, medications, or viral conditions like hand-foot-and-mouth disease. While usually painless, mild discomfort may occur if the nail detaches. Treatment focuses on addressing the underlying cause, with the nail typically regrowing over time. </string>
    <string name="melanonychia">Melanonychia is characterized by dark or black pigmentation in the nail plate, often caused by an increase in melanin. It can present as vertical streaks or diffuse discoloration. While it may be linked to benign causes like trauma or medications, it can also signal more serious conditions such as melanoma. Diagnosis typically involves clinical examination and may require further tests. Treatment depends on the underlying cause, ranging from addressing benign issues to treating more serious conditions like cancer.</string>

    <string name="Chloronychia">Chloronychia, or "green nail syndrome," is a condition caused by an infection with Pseudomonas aeruginosa bacteria, leading to a greenish discoloration of the nails, often affecting fingernails. It commonly occurs in individuals who frequently have their hands in water or wear gloves for long periods. While the primary symptom is discoloration, prolonged infection can cause the nail to lift or detach, accompanied by mild tenderness or discomfort.</string>

    <string name="Anonychia">Anonychia is a condition where nails on the fingers or toes are either absent or develop abnormally. This may occur from birth (congenital) or arise later due to injury or illness. The nails might be missing entirely or appear unusually small, thin, or malformed. While the condition itself is typically painless, the exposed fingertips and toes can be more sensitive without nail protection, which may affect grip and fine motor abilities.</string>
    <string name="hemetuema">A subungual hematoma is the accumulation of blood beneath the nail, typically caused by trauma or injury, leading to discoloration (red, purple, or black) and pain. The condition occurs when blood vessels under the nail rupture, often from crush injuries or repetitive trauma. Treatment may involve draining the blood to relieve pressure, or it may heal on its own. The nail usually regrows over time, though this can take several months.</string>
    <string name="pincer">Pincer nails, or "trumpet nails," occur when the nails curve inward, often causing pain, redness, and swelling, especially at the edges. This condition can be congenital or acquired due to factors like improper nail trimming, trauma, or underlying conditions such as psoriasis or fungal infections. Treatment focuses on relieving pressure and may involve addressing the cause or, in severe cases, surgical correction.</string>
    <string name="snap_tips1">• Make sure to capture fingernails from all angles of the hand for accurate analysis of any detected diseases. Having comprehensive images helps in better understanding color and texture.
</string>
    <string name="snap_tips2">• To ensure precise detection, only capture one fingernail at a time. Avoid including other nails in your photos to prevent misleading.
</string>
    <string name="snap_tips3">• Place the fingernail inside the provided marker for consistent size and framing, which enhances the accuracy of disease analysis.</string>
    <string name="snap_tips4">• Take clear, well-lit photos to ensure precise results. Poor lighting or unclear images can affect the accuracy of disease detection. Make sure the fingernails are in focus and the image is free of blurs or distractions.</string>

</resources>